John and Ginny Dildine collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Sound Recordings
  - AFC 1975/001: SR142, Recorded: 1964, RXG 0802; 29:52
    29:52 Fade out and End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR143, Recorded: 1964, RXG 0803; 29:52
    There are two parts to this John Dildine tape. The first centers on the Reverend Robert Wilkins; the second on Bob and Evelyn Beers. There is no indication that this was produced for a radio broadcast. This is a duplicate of SR142.
  - AFC 1975/001: SR144, Recorded: ca. 1962-1963, RXG 0804; 28:42
    This tape is a copy of SR068. It was recorded for a John Dildine radio broadcast. The Christenson portion is an extract of SR062. He also interviews Tossi Aaron and Seamus Ennis.
    16:06 Didline introduces Tossi Aaron.
    27:29 Unidentified song Ennis [penny whistle]
    28:08 Ennis cites a short [poem].
  - AFC 1975/001: SR145 (1), Recorded: ca. 1963, RXG 0805; 11:36
    This tape is the continuation of a recording for a John Dildine radio broadcast, an interview with Judy Collins. She has just released an album called "Judy Collins #3." No songs are played on this tape. The first part of the interview is on SR071.
    0:23 Dildine says that the previous song was "The Dove" performed by Judy Collins. Dildine and Dildine talk about conservation. Dildine talks about the [Mayone Reserve] where he has bought property. Collins introduces the next song "The Ballad of the Deportees." It is not played on this tape.
    6:46 Dildine and Collins talk about the previous song. Dildine asks for one final song. They talk about contemporary song writers who inspire Collins. They talk about the changing times and the contemporary folk movement. Collins introduces the next song "Farewell" which is a Bob Dylan version of a traditional song "The Leaving of Liverpool." It is not played on this tape.
  - AFC 1975/001: SR145 (2), Recorded: ca. 1963, RXG 0805; 11:36
    This is a portion of a John Dildine radio broadcast. He plays recordings by various people.
    Start An unidentified woman singing a cappella.
    0:50 Dildine starts a Ewan MacColl song then says he'll not play it on the air. He turns
    the record over to play the next song.
    1:36 "Kissins Nae Sin" Ewan MacColl, a cappella
    2:26 "Get Away, Old man, Get Away" Peggy Seeger and Ewan MacColl, banjo
    4:31 Dildine says he will play a version of a "broken token" ballad.
    5:16 "Pretty Fair Maid" or "The Sailor's Return" Peggy Seeger, autoharp
    8:42 Dildine talks about a Mike Seeger recording of autoharp music.
    9:37 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR145 (3), Recorded: ca. 1963, RXG 0805; 10:31
    This is a recording made for a radio broadcast called "Unitarians Speak."
    Start An orchestral version of "Greensleeves." A man reads a quote about man and his beliefs.
    1:27 The announcer talks about the previous quote. He introduces the radio broadcast of Unitarians Speak. He introduces the speaker, Dr. Lawrence Staples. His topic is: "Why This Unitarian Growth."
    2:25 Dr. Staples speaking
    10:24 End of recording, before Dr. Staples is finished.
  - AFC 1975/001: SR146, Recorded: undated, RAA 54547; [no tape log is available for this item]
  - AFC 1975/001: SR147, Recorded: undated, RAA 54548; [no tape log is available for this item]
  - AFC 1975/001: SR148, Recorded: undated, RXG 0822; [no tape log is available for this item]
    [tape box reads "Paley - Willie Moore / Down by the River / Fly Around / Soldiers Joy" ]
  - AFC 1975/001: SR149, Recorded: unknown, RXG 0806; 27:37
    This appears to be the dub of a record by an unidentified performer. A man sings, plays guitar, harmonics and Kazoo.
    Start ["Hobo You can't Ride This Train"] talking and vocal, guitar and harmonica
    4:46 ["I Left My Baby and I'll Tell You the Reason Why"] or perhaps ["Take It Slow and Easy If You Wanna Get Along with Me"] vocal, guitar, harmonica and kazoo
    7:35 "The Monkey and the Engineer" vocal, guitar, harmonica
    9:58 "A New Corrinne" vocal, guitar, harmonica and kazoo
    12:55 introduced as "an old blues of mine" guitar solo
    15:44 ["I'm Runnin' Wild"] vocal, guitar, harmonica and kazoo
    18:24 first line is: "Hey Baby, Hey Baby, Hey, Hey" vocal, guitar, and harmonica
    21:38 first line is: "Read It in the Bible" vocal, guitar, harmonica and kazoo
    24:54 first line is: "Straighten Up Baby, You're the One" vocal, guitar, harmonica and kazoo
    27:21 End of recording
    27:37 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR150, Recorded: unknown, RXG 0807; 27:37
    This appears to be the dub of one or two records. The first three songs are by Jesse Fuller. The remaining songs are by an unidentified performer, perhaps the same performer as on SR149.
    Start An unidentified waltz Fuller, guitar, harmonica kazoo and [high hat]
    3:08 first line is "This job I've gotten is a little too hard" Fuller, vocal, guitar, harmonica, kazoo and [high hat]
    6:13 first line is "Once I used to hang around and be in the show" Fuller, vocal, guitar, harmonica, kazoo and [high hat]
    [The following song are by an unidentified performer.]
    9:15 first line is "I [?] in Baltimore knocking on my door" vocal, guitar, harmonica and tap dance
    13:22 "Railroad Work Song" vocal, guitar, harmonica and kazoo
    19:16 "Shove 'em Over" vocal and a rhythm instrument
    20:24 "John Henry" vocal and guitar
    27:02 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR151 (1), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0808; 30:02
    This appears to be a dub from three records. The first two songs are by an unidentified female singer. The next eight songs are by an unidentified male Irish singer. The final song is by an unidentified guitar player.
    0:19 "Malagueña" female singer, guitar
    3:04 "Summertime" female singer, guitar
    5:27 blank
    6:10 "As I Roved Out" male singer, guitar
    8:55 "An Cat Dubh" (The Foggy Dew) male singer, guitar
    16:06 "Mrs. McGrath" male singer, guitar and tin whistle
    14:58 "Bold O'Donohue" male singer, guitar
    16:42 ["Connemara Cradle Song"] male singer, guitar
    19:22 "The Irish Rover" male singer, guitar and tin whistle
    21:35 blank
    22:13 ["Little Beggar Man"] male singer, banjo
    23:55 "The Butcher Boy" male singer, guitar
    27:30 unidentified blues solo guitar
    30:02 End of recording, before end of song
  - AFC 1975/001: SR151 (2), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0808; 30:02
    This is probably a dub of a record by an unidentified female singer.
    0:18 "House of the Rising Sun" vocal, guitar
    2:55 "The Water is Wide" vocal, guitar
    6:50 unidentified gospel song vocal, guitar
    7:46 "Mary, What You Gonna Call Your Pretty Little Baby" vocal, guitar
    11:20 unidentified song in Spanish vocal, guitar
    12:52 "Go Away from My Window" vocal, guitar
    16:00 "Open the Door Softly" vocal, guitar
    19:08 unidentified song vocal, guitar
    20:41 unidentified song vocal, guitar
    23:11 "If I Had a Ribbon Bow" vocal, guitar
    25:38 unidentified song vocal, guitar
    28:37 Conclusion of a of a radio called Pipeline Radio
  - AFC 1975/001: SR152 (1), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0809; 30:22
    This is most probably a dub of a record by Ewan MacColl and Peggy Seeger.
    0:18 "Iron Horse" MacColl, banjo
    2:12 "Durham Lockout" MacColl, guitar
    5:31 "The Calton Weaver" also known as "Nancy Whiskey" MacColl and Seeger, banjo
    7:47 unidentified song MacColl, guitar
    9:30 blank
    9:58 "Johnny Lad" MacColl and Seeger, banjo
    12:32 "The False Lover won Back" MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    17:38 ["Aiken Drum"] MacColl and Seeger, banjo
    19:44 "The Gardiner" MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    24:28 [may be "The Maid Went to the Mill" or "Miller and the Maid"] MacColl and Seeger, banjo
    26:30 "Elfin Nights" MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    30:22 End of recording before the song ends
  - AFC 1975/001: SR152 (2), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0809; 30:22
    This is most probably a dub of a record by Ewan MacColl and Peggy Seeger. The recording quality is not good and MacColl sings many of the songs in a dialect. These two things make it very difficult to understand the lyrics.
    Start ["Blow, Ye Winds, Blow"] MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    4:23 "Banks of the Nile" MacColl, guitar
    8:32 Blank
    9:17 unidentified song MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    13:31 unidentified song MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    15:19 unidentified song MacColl, banjo
    18:32 unidentified song MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    20:53 ["The Bonnie Lass O'Fyvie"] unidentified song MacColl and Seeger, banjo
    24:51 unidentified song MacColl, guitar
    27:16 ["Lord Thomas and the Fair Ellender"] MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    30:13 End of recording
  - AFC 1975/001: SR153 (1), Recorded: ca. 1958, RXG 0810; 32:17
    The first part of this SR is most probably a dub of a record by Ewan MacColl and Peggy Seeger. The second part is a recording made for a portion of a radio broadcast called "Pipeline."
    Start ["A Pretty Fair Maid in the Garden" also known as "John Riley"] Seeger, autoharp
    3:43 ["The Trooper and the Fair Maid"] MacColl and Seeger, banjo
    7:44 first line: "Where are the flowers, the flowers that open and bloom in the sun" Seeger, guitar
    11:17 "The Little turtle Dove" MacColl, a cappella
    13:35 Blank, end of Dildine recording
    15:30 Transcription of a radio broadcast called "Pipeline." The program is introduced by Jim [Toehill].
    14:30 "You Better Go Now" Polly Bergen
    17:10 Toehill speaks about the Republican Party and the liberal labor point of view.
    21:52 "Easy to Say" Johnny Mathis
    24:35 Toehill introduces an interview with Andrew J. Biehill of the AFofL/CIO, The interview follows.
    32:14 Toehill says "thank you."
    32:17 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR153 (2), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0810; 32:17
    This is probably a dub of a record by Ewan MacColl and Peggy Seeger record.
    Start first line: "My husband was a wealthy merchant, where he is I do not know" MacColl and Seeger, guitar
    2:30 first line: "When first to this city of Dundee I came" MacColl, a cappella
    4:55 first line: "My dear the time has come when you and I must part" Seeger, banjo
    8:40 unidentified song MacColl, a cappella
    12:25 "The Dark Eyed Sailor" Seeger, guitar
    16:48 first line: "Here my darling, here is a letter and the hand that held the pen" MacColl, banjo
    19:09 first line: "Come all you young fair maids" Seeger, a cappella
    20:27 unidentified song MacColl, [concertina]
    22:46 "Seven Deadly Sins" MacColl, a cappella
    23:37 "Get Away Old Man" MacColl and Seeger, banjo
    25:47 "The Manchester Angel" MacColl, guitar and [concertina]
    30:24 End of recording
    32:17 END
  - AFC 1975/001: SR154 (1), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0811; 30:02
    This is a recording of one or more banjo players, fiddlers and vocalists. None of the performers are identified. None of the musical selections are identified. There is also a short interview and discussion between a man a banjo player and a woman a fiddle player. At about 20 minutes into the SR the sound recording starts to deteriorate. It gets distorted, "muddy" and loses volume.
    Start unidentified song banjo solo
    1:40 unidentified song banjo solo
    2:58 unidentified song banjo solo
    4:23 unidentified song banjo solo
    5:42 unidentified song banjo solo
    6:54 unidentified song banjo solo
    8:23 unidentified song banjo solo
    9:48 unidentified song fiddle solo
    11:12 unidentified song fiddle solo
    12:07 unidentified song fiddle solo
    13:33 Conversation: A male interviewer [the banjo player] interviews a woman [the fiddle player]. He calls her Granny. Her father [Van Sage] was from Grayson County.
    15:11 unidentified song banjo solo
    16:14 unidentified song banjo solo
    17:22 unidentified song fiddle solo
    18:42 unidentified song banjo solo
    20:12 unidentified song fiddle and vocal
    21:24 unidentified song fiddle, banjo and vocal
    23:42 ["Moonshiner"] a cappella vocal (male)
    25:42 unidentified song banjo and vocal
    29:24 End of recording
  - AFC 1975/001: SR154 (2), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0811; 31:02
    At the beginning of the SR there is a banjo solo. However, starting at 01:22 the recording quality deteriorates such that the sound is unintelligible. There is distortion and an over dub of a different program which seems to be recorded at a different speed.
    0:23 unidentified banjo tune unidentified performer
    1:22 unintelligible sound recording
    31:02 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR155 (1), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0823; 15:41
    This is a set of 5 songs by one or more unidentified string bands. The recording quality of the first three songs is not good, making it difficult to identify the songs. The recording quality of the final two songs is much better.
    Start Unintelligible recording of an unidentified string band.
    3:12 "Dixie" unidentified string band
    6:27 Unintelligible recording of an unidentified string band.
    9:34 "Franklin D. Roosevelt's Back Again" unidentified string band
    12:32 "The Democratic Donkey (Is in His Stall Again)" unidentified string band
    15:41 End
  - AFC 1975/001: SR155 (2), Recorded: unknown, RXG 0823; 15:51
    This is asset of 5 seemingly unrelated songs.
    Start ["Cluck Old Hen"] unidentified string band
    02:57 unidentified instrumental unidentified string band
    06:09 unidentified instrumental unidentified string band
    07:50 unidentified instrumental unidentified string band [Sam McGee]
    11:11 ["Down to the Depot"] or ["The brakeman's Blues"] unidentified singer, guitar
    14:45 guitar solo unidentified performer
    15:51 End - before the end of the song